harshjha872@gmail.com

Harsh Jha

harshv1.vercel.app | LinkedIn | GitHub

+91-8738066880

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled Fullstack developer with over **1.5 years of experience** in **HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node.js**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React, Next.js and Vue.js** and experience with REST APIs and Express.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Typescript, Javascript, C/C++, HTML, CSS **Frameworks** : React.js, Next.js, Express, Node.js, Vue.js, Nuxt

Libraries : Redux, Vuex, Tailwind CSS, Vuetify, Material, Shadcn/ui, Prisma, Mongoose, Socket.io

Databases : MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Supabase

Dev Tools: VS Code, Git/Github, REST APIs, Postman, Docker, Microsoft Azure Storage Explorer, JSON, Vite, Vercel

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

SpectroNOVA

Oct 2023 - Present

Remote – Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Designed and documented reusable UI components with smooth animations, enhancing consistency and speed
- Enhanced product stability by resolving bugs in the company's product
- Contributed to effective workload management and timely delivery through active participation in planning calls
- Created a process visualization dashboard to provide clients with insights and improve decision-making
- Ensured code quality by collaborating on and conducting 50+ code reviews

Full-stack Developer

Constems-Al Systems

Apr 2023 – Sept 2023

Remote - Noida, Uttar Pradesh

- Developed 25+ UIs and full-stack solutions for client projects with modern technologies
- Implemented an email service with Node.js and Express, increasing operational efficiency by 50%
- Optimized RESTful APIs with large datasets, improving data retrieval speed by 25%
- Created backend solutions and automated scripts, saving 10+ hours of work weekly
- Managed an ATMS web application, ensuring seamless data monitoring for 35,000 vehicles daily
- Led the development of a Reporting tool, facilitating weekly reports for 70+ clients by an operational team

PROJECTS

Al News

Typescript, Next.js, Shadcn/ui, Tailwind CSS, PostgreSQL, Prisma

Source Code

- · Launched a web app for AI news with an integrated data feed for current trends
- Added a subscription feature for personalized AI news emails, boosting user engagement

MoviesSage

Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Redux, MongoDB

Source Code

- Hosted a responsive movies web app with public API integration
- Tailored the login/signup functionality with credentials and API endpoints
- Displayed movie details, ratings, stars, plots, and allowing users to **bookmark** a movie

EDUCATION

KIET Group Of Institutions

Bachelor of Technology, ECE

Ghaziabad 2019 - 2023

ACHIEVEMENTS AND EXTRACURRICULAR

- 5 stars in hackerrank (C++ programming)
- · Solved 150+ data structures and algorithm problems
- · Participated in different hackathons like Cicada, Bhilai Hacks